<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>
        BASIC blog full text feed    </title>
        <link href="blog/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    
        <link href="/307S2011/"/>
    
        
    <updated>2011-12-14T10:38:47Z</updated>

    <id>/307S2011/blog/atom.xml/</id>

            <entry>
            <title type="html">History- making me sweat</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/history-making-me-sweat.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-25T20:27:46Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-25T20:27:46Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/history-making-me-sweat.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This last class period put me under some serious historical duress. We went around the room and spoke about our specific historical topics but lo and behold, mine needs help. I am in the process of doing more research and visiting good old John Hodges and his special collections this Monday and hope I can get this hammered down so I can begin to compile sources. We read Yale&amp;#8217;s syllabus for writing a senior thesis in history and this just stressed me further. This 40 pages is already looming over me and I am anxious about its completion. There were several essays with helpful advice in this syllabus though and they pertained to this fear I am experiencing as well as the process of choosing a topic. Several things that were stressed in this guide also include the process of editing in order to keep one on track as well as the debate between outlining or not. I tend to be the type of person who works without an outline, but for a project this large I think this would cause me to analyze in circles. I visited a man in special collections today and he seemed a little wary about my topic as well but I am going in Tuesday morning to examine more primary sources. I know this topic won&amp;#8217;t fall out of the sky, but one can dream. Looking forward to&amp;nbsp;Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=39&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">The End of 307</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/the-end-of-307.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-24T11:46:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-24T11:46:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/the-end-of-307.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;It&amp;#8217;s really hard to believe that this is our last blog and more importantly our last week of 307. &amp;nbsp;Looking back at the schedule of readings, William Cronon&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;&lt;i&gt;Getting Ready to Do History&lt;/i&gt;&amp;#8221; from week 2 jumped out at me. &amp;nbsp;14 weeks separated, are we actually ready to &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;DO&lt;/span&gt; history? &amp;nbsp;Will we be able to amalgamate occasionally problematic sources into an appropriate interpretative framework, using the appropriate methodology? &amp;nbsp;Is History writing even an approachable endeavor in the post-linguistic turn world? &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; I can&amp;#8217;t say I wasn&amp;#8217;t anxious coming into 307 and I can&amp;#8217;t honestly say I&amp;#8217;m not anxious moving forward into 407. &amp;nbsp;Yet, that anxiety is now mixed with a comforting sense of confidence. &amp;nbsp;I know how to discover the sources, I know how to critically analyze them, and I know how to transform these objects of research into the thesis of an argument. &amp;nbsp;The only thing left to do is to do the history itself: enmesh myself in the documents of yesterday and hope that I can resurface on the other side with a provocative and objective work of historical scholarship.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Reading the Yale Senior Essay Handbook definitely made me consider the prospects of devoting my entire senior year to the likes of a 50-page essay. &amp;nbsp;Surely there will be countless hours of time devoted to both research and writing over the coming year. &amp;nbsp;However, as the Handbook insinuated, I feel similarly that the senior paper will be a crowning culmination of my four years at the University of Tennessee. &amp;nbsp;There were a couple of things outlined by the Senior Essay Handbook that I liked in particular. &amp;nbsp;First of all, I like the idea of having a rigid timetable to work with. &amp;nbsp;The step-to-step process offered by Yale, wherein one moves from a research plan to a prospectus to a draft to a final product, helps me develop a methodology that works with my schedule, based on the knowledge of forthcoming due dates. &amp;nbsp;I was also attracted to the proposed idea of writing the research paper in small subsections. &amp;nbsp;Normally when I sit down to write out any sort of essay I first start by writing a single sentence I&amp;#8217;d like to incorporate in the finished product. &amp;nbsp;The paper comes together from this starting point as I extrapolate outward and build the whole out of various pieces. &amp;nbsp;In many ways this approach is similar to dividing the paper into perhaps 10, 5-page papers, but simply on a smaller scale. &amp;nbsp;Sometimes I do feel like the strategy hurts the narrative flow of the paper, yet usually this can be counter-balanced by appropriate transitions.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-7910301908961520490?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Scan this blog!</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/scan-this-blog.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-23T17:24:02Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-23T17:24:02Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/scan-this-blog.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;While I was away at camp, the class read two very interesting articles regarding source digitization and archival preservation. The first article was published in the New York Times and explored a topic I was aware of but was ignorant of its depth and consequence. In &lt;em&gt;Scan This Book!&lt;/em&gt;, Kevin Kelly discusses the promise and difficulties surrounding the placement of all the world&amp;#8217;s work (especially books) on the web. He stresses the dynamic nature of this new database, and the relationships amongst works would be invaluable into learning and gaining new insights into what we already know. This would be invaluable in our field of history. If one could search the masses of primary sources, journal articles, and books surrounding a topic and employ the relationships outlined, there would be masses of new and innovative work produced. I can barely comprehend the effects this universal library would have upon the field of history. The problems regarding this digitization revolve around the hazy area of copyrights. With many copyrights being difficult to trace and copyright laws extending the length of these rights for ridiculous periods of time, there is a legal hurricane around this area. In the end, I side with Google, and see this potential library as the word&amp;#8217;s greatest&amp;nbsp;invention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second article, written by Louis Bickford, addressed the topic of the preservation of the documents produced by HRGNOs in the southern cone of South America. This region has experienced recent rights violations and the people are divided between remembering/addressing and forgetting/ignoring these atrocities. One can understand both points of view, but to forget can almost erase an event from history as shown by the genocide in the Belgian Congo. This clearly supports the stance of remembrance, and while it takes time for a nation to revisit the events, they must be aware of the preservation of documents, especially those from HRGNOs. Bickford stresses that this is absent in this southern cone and efforts must be increased to archive these materials. This is important to us because we understand the necessity of primary documents to revisit, reconstruct, and analyze these past events. While some want to forget, remembering will create a greater sense of appreciation for those who endured and will foster a society more vigilant of possible&amp;nbsp;violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/33/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=33&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Our Brand is Deception</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/None.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-22T18:36:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-22T18:36:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/None.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“For better or worse, neoliberalism-with a familiar emphasis on free trade, export production, and the doctrine of comparative advantage-reigned supreme in Latin America at the turn of the third millennium.”&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This week’s movie “Our Brand Is Crisis” was important in explaining two policies that relate to the latest developments in Latin America. These are the United States continued blind influence on the region with no thought to the effect on the actual people. Also the other development is that the people in Latin America especially the indigenous were no longer willing to accept the status quo and were standing up against their oppressors. This neoliberalism that is talked about in John Charles Chasteen’s book “Born in Blood and Fire” had an urgent flare in Latin America. The policy was fueled in more by the United States that agreed with the policy. So how did an area fueled in nationalistic ideologies become so globalist? &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;To answer those questions one has to look at closer at the actual people being effected and participating. One sector of society was benefitting, the middle class and above. But, in reflection there was a whole portion of society mostly the indigenous that had not forgotten their nationalistic roots and were not willing to go along with the cogs of the neoliberal globalization politics. In the face of all of this as Chasteen explains, a reconceptulization of the race relations in the region was taking place. People used nationalist rhetoric of the past to instill their own fight for their rights in the region. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;One important lesson that the movie and Chasteen touches on is that the United States understanding of the people residing in Latin America needs to be reshaped if there is going to be any kind of positive relations between the two areas. Chasteen explains that the United States sees all peoples of Latin America as Latinos. He shows how this is only a concept that applies once they immigrate to the United States where they become an amalgamated whole under the “umbrella” name Latinos. The actual people of the region see themselves as Bolivians, Mexicans, Brazilians, and so on. To understand this is to show that each country has a history that must be understood and the effect that this still has on their country today. In the case of Bolivia, the United States strategists did not understand that protesting in the street is the way that their people effect political change. In their push towards globalization in these countries they forgot the peoples that were being marginalized. They forgot these people’s histories and their engrained beliefs that they would forever stand for. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“Increasing poverty, stagnant or falling real wages, and a further and steady widening of the distribution of income in virtually every nation has also become omnipresent and largely ignored social context of the neoliberal era.”&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In James Cypher’s article on the “Washington Consensus” explains the essential weaknesses of neoliberal economics in Latin America. One argument he makes is that the kind of funds that came into the Latin American countries was one very limited in who they helped and two did not bring the employment that they promised. This is one argument that the people in the movie make against Goni’s own policies from his first presidency from 1993 or 1997. They say that although he created social security he did not bring an increase in jobs whatsoever. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The article by John Perkins reveals the understanding these people have in what they are doing and the harmful effects that it has on these countries. But what is even more startling is that they know what they are doing. They want these countries that they are lending to, to be forever politically and economically tied to them. They do enough to make the highest elite in the countries happy and forget the rest. They willingly deceit these people to make larger loans than they know they can afford. They also in the process break down the fragile government structure in that country by alleviating the people’s trust in their government. It is very much like the movie when the strategists may not know or care if Guni was the right candidate for that country but they still made sure he got into power with deceptive tactics. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;Till next week,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-8369777515040481223?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">“Focus on the journey, not the destination. Joy is found not in finishing an activity but in doing it.”</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/e2809cfocus-on-the-journey-not-the-destination-joy-is-found-not-in-finishing-an-activity-but-in-doing-it-e2809d.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-22T15:24:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-22T15:24:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/e2809cfocus-on-the-journey-not-the-destination-joy-is-found-not-in-finishing-an-activity-but-in-doing-it-e2809d.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“The historical dimension in every object, person, and occurrence provokes our questions and provides an important part of our understanding”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;If I can say that I learned anything this semester I would say that I learned that historiography goes beyond the Civil War. But the Civil War is still a very relatable example for most things!! Also, having to accept that the sole female in the class makes mistakes in regard to assuming the gender of authors. That slip up will probably live with me for the rest of my life. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;For most of the semester I have live in a cloud of self-confidence when it came to writing this thesis paper. I have felt that from my combined previous experience and from what I have learned this semester that I could pull out a senior thesis. I did not give any hesitation to this fact. But, honestly after reading the Yale Guide I became nervous when it comes to the paper. This guide should have had the reverse effect. While it spells out everything you should do it gives great advice on how to efficiently do your thesis and make it a wonderful rewarding experience. My major worry when looking at my topic and next year is my thesis. I worry that I have a good subject and a really great resource of primary sources but that I will not be able to translate the information into a significant argument about or against the War Commission. I would like to talk about veteran’s choices versus the War Commission choices. But I am worried that this is not going to be enough of an argument. Before I had a bunch of good arguments but not one strong one. Hopefully through significant research into the subject I can develop a strong central argument. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“History making and history made are scientifically inseparable and separately unmeaning.” &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This semester I have completely reformed my idea of how you develop a competent thesis. I feel that everything I have done before now was not properly done. From learning from nineteenth century scholars such as Carl Becker and Lord Acton; Even more importantly Wilhelm Von Humboldt and Leopold Von Ranke. The professionalization of the academic historical field created a guild and a set of steps to get into that field. This process of professionalization has set up the idea that every conclusion is contingent on evidentiary practice. Also learning about the important shift from great man history to history done from below. The impact of historical Marxism on this. Learning that structures are not the patterned social practices that make up social systems, but the principles that pattern these practices. A historian cannot use ethnocentrism when they are deconstructing a society. Just as language is not transparent, neither is society. Everything must be taken in it’s own context. Learning the methods of how to read primary sources was incredibly important also. Before this semester I always though you just read primary sources without any kind of method. But using your primary sources as proper evidence to a well backed up argument will make my paper stronger. I think our argument about context was very helpful to me. The time period, the structures, the author’s position, and the intended audience are all important. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Another important aspect is learning the object of the research and the subject of the argument. Discovering the difference between these two helped me and will help me to make a paper that has a reason. A paper that is not just information but a well structured argument. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&amp;nbsp;TIll next week,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-726726112738767153?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Archival Imperative</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/archival-imperative.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-19T16:06:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-19T16:06:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/archival-imperative.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;         &lt;/span&gt;The first article by Louis Bickford chronicled the archival imperative in Chile, Argentina, and Uruguay. &amp;nbsp;Bickford focused specifically within the realm of human rights&amp;#8217; documents, discussing the dire need to archive past human rights&amp;#8217; atrocities. &amp;nbsp;Far too often these documents are found sitting in dusty boxes, unorganized, and shoved into the most readily available space. &amp;nbsp;Moreover, Bickford identifies an obvious division between those whom stress remembering and those whom advocate forgetting their state&amp;#8217;s traumatic past. &amp;nbsp;Another obstacle to appropriate human rights&amp;#8217; archiving is the matter of money, as the archives in Chile, Argentina, and Uruguay have very small, insufficiently funded budgets. &amp;nbsp;Bickford spends time identifying the various documents created by the HRNGOs on a country-by-country basis and then delves into her own well-developed archival construction plan. &amp;nbsp;She lays out a path that could result in appropriate archival preservation but doesn&amp;#8217;t really deal with how these archives could get funding for the process. &amp;nbsp;State and private support are nearly non-existent and I just don&amp;#8217;t see the archives being able to afford microform machines, film, or hardware on their own.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;         &lt;/span&gt;The second article was entitled &lt;i&gt;Scan This!&lt;/i&gt; by Kevin Kelly of Wired Magazine. &amp;nbsp;Currently I&amp;#8217;m using Google&amp;#8217;s Chrome browser to surf the web, I passed Spanish thanks to Google Translate, and now my phone is even running Google&amp;#8217;s own operating system. &amp;nbsp;It seems as if there are no limitations to Google&amp;#8217;s expanding reach, but&amp;#8230; a universal library? &amp;nbsp;A library containing every facet of human knowledge, ranging from every text written to every picture taken? Impossible. &amp;nbsp;Yet, in today&amp;#8217;s world of increasing archival preservation, where we have &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;SUV&lt;/span&gt;-sized robot photocopiers, is it really that impossible?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;         &lt;/span&gt;It is unfortunate that almost all intellectual property originating in today&amp;#8217;s world is subject to such stringent copyright laws. &amp;nbsp;However, as Kevin Kelly points out, copyright laws may be the last saving grace of an already failing business model. &amp;nbsp;The world in 2011 is a fast-moving, technologically centric place where information can easily be transmitted with the click of a mouse. &amp;nbsp;Just consider the music industry and their attempts to regulate song distribution with tight copyright laws. &amp;nbsp;If I were so willing, it would be easy to circumvent these restrictions and obtain almost any song without cost and with minimal fear of repercussions. This is an obvious example of the legal clash between the physical copy and the searchable Web, a clash which Kelly promises will be a long one. &amp;nbsp;In the case of books, I feel as if there is a clear avenue for Google to pursue the 75% of dark-horse books with no clear copyright owners. &amp;nbsp;These books need to be returned to the &amp;#8216;public sphere&amp;#8217; where they can help deepen our cultural and historical knowledge. As books become cross-linked with one another and begin to sport fancy user-generated tags, I don&amp;#8217;t feel as if the historian&amp;#8217;s job becomes easier per se. &amp;nbsp;One would think that the sheer amount of available information would ideally lead to new histories or perhaps at least the reimagining of past histories. &amp;nbsp;As is obvious, a universal library with infinite primary and secondary digitized sources would be the ultimate benefactor for any research. &amp;nbsp;However, as each researcher looked for the perfect amalgamation of all sources into the perfect interpretative framework, it seems like the researcher&amp;#8217;s job difficulty could increase exponentially.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-2420051248699584239?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Doctor Strangelove</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/doctor-strangelove.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-19T13:24:03Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-19T13:24:03Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/doctor-strangelove.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;I am writing about the National Security Archive, which their website describes as, “An independent non-governmental research institute and library located at The George Washington University, the Archive collects and publishes declassified documents obtained through the Freedom of Information Act.” I had never heard of this website, but it appears to be source for &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;CIA&lt;/span&gt;, Nuclear Policy and a whole host of information that make conspiracy theorists toes tingle. This post will focus on a film produced by the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;U.S.&lt;/span&gt; Air Force in the mid 1950s. From a historiographical point of view, I believe it gives some insight into the thought process of the senior nuclear policy makers in the Pentagon. This piece could definitely provide some context for a person studying the Cuban Missile Crisis for example. The film demonstrates a kind of automatic response to information that does not seem to be verified by multiple sources. The film had a very “Dr. Strangelove” feel to it, which was scary for a guy who used to go through the crawl under you elementary school desk drill. The write up for the film said, “By the early 1950s, senior military planners and defense officials had begun considering the possibility of pre-emptive attacks on the basis of strategic warning; that is, if the United States intelligence warning system collected reliable information on an impending Soviet attack, decision-makers could approve strikes against Soviet military forces to disrupt it.”&lt;a title=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://williambuie.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post-new.php#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Let’s take them out before they take us out. It scares me to think how close we really were to completely destroying the Earth, and while the nuclear threat is still a very real and present danger, the world is no doubt safer now that the Cold War is over. Imagine if George W. Bush, as his team of Neo-Cons, were in power during the Cuban Missile Crisis in 1962. We might not be here today, or if we were the place might look like a Cormac McCarthy&amp;nbsp;novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr align=&#34;left&#34; size=&#34;1&#34; width=&#34;33%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;http://williambuie.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post-new.php#_ftnref1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; William Burr, “‘Nobody Wins a Nuclear War’ But ‘Success’ is Possible&lt;br /&gt;
Mixed Message of 1950s Air Force Film on a U.S.-Soviet Conflict,” &lt;em&gt;National Security Archive, &lt;/em&gt;National Security Archive Electronic Briefing Book No. 336, date accessed April 19, 2011,&amp;nbsp;http://www.gwu.edu/~nsarchiv/nukevault/ebb336/index.htm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/42/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=42&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">My Revisionist Point of View</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/my-revisionist-point-of-view.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-14T04:07:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-14T04:07:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/my-revisionist-point-of-view.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The articles this week are teaching us about archiving and the very important positives and negatives that can come from trying to save our precious historical resources. The first article by Louis Bickford, discussed the preservation of documents relating to human rights injustices in the Southern Cone of Latin America. These documents specifically ones produced by HRNGOs stand in grave danger of being reduced to dust because of improper treatment of these documents. One argument for why this has occurred is because there has not been enough time to pass for the country to really realize the importance of discussing nationally what atrocities have occurred in their country. They give a prime example that it took almost a hundred years before the United States could really discuss its activity in the transatlantic slave trade. One of the biggest dangers that makes the documentation that they do have so important is that many documents were destroyed to try to cover up what has occurred. This is inherent in nations wanting to manipulate their past’s history. Stemming from some nation’s do not want their archives of human rights problems to become available because they know people will research it and find out about it. Also the historiography on that subject matter will expand internationally. Within this there are two camps that have developed on who stress remembering the other who advocate forgetting. These arguments are not new in the study of history. These arguments about the importance of remembering history have come up in a number of dialogues. One part of this facing the development of these archives is budgets. If these government believe that they should leave their pasts behind, they are not going to fund projects that support the progression of the remembrance of their past. There have been strides made in these countries to try to gather these materials but have fallen short in preservation. One discussion that has come up a number of times this semester is privatization. Just because it needs to be kept private does not mean it should not be preserved. It still could tell us something in the future. Another discussion is releasing these documents to libraries and archives in other countries. Some are very unwilling to do this and will be a time limit on when they can have them available. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;I have always been very against using online archives as a major resource for primary research. But, after looking at these websites I am convinced that it is a positive move not just for preservation but also for the berth of information that we can get now with archives being on a website. On the National Security Archive the Chiquita papers intrigued me. I was so impressed how looking at the copy on the website was pretty close to having that document in your hand. What made them even more useful than even being at the archive was that it gave a lot of background information on the individual archives. This made them even more powerful. I have seen on other websites how works that have to be transcribed are already done for you such as with the Lincoln Papers at the Library Congress where 20,000 of Lincoln’s papers were transcribed and digitized. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Cambria; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-ascii-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family: &amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-bidi; mso-fareast-font-family: Cambria; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-hansi-theme-font: minor-latin;&#34;&gt;The next article “Scan this Book!” reveals the impact of digitizing books. This was a startling article because I had not thought about how far this could go in a number of years. Kevin Kelly compares the potential wealth that will be in a digital archive to the library at Alexandria. One of the impacts that he says is that no book will be an island. No book is isolated in itself. Especially with a search engine, before a person had to do the legwork to the see the pertinence of a book. Now they can have a search that picks what is pertinent for them. This will also help people to pull sections from different books. Books will no longer be complete entities in themselves. They will be mixed with other books to create interwebs. A couple positive changes that Kelly makes is that one it will increase readership especially on items with very few readership at the moment. The feeling of completeness and authority over having it all in one place will increase. For me I see the importance of works being on the computer but I am partial&amp;nbsp;to pen and paper.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-family: Cambria;&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-family: Cambria;&#34;&gt;Till next week,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-style-span&#34; style=&#34;font-family: Cambria;&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Cambria; font-size: 12.0pt; mso-ansi-language: EN-US; mso-ascii-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-bidi-font-family: &amp;quot;Times New Roman&amp;quot;; mso-bidi-theme-font: minor-bidi; mso-fareast-font-family: Cambria; mso-fareast-language: EN-US; mso-fareast-theme-font: minor-latin; mso-hansi-theme-font: minor-latin;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-8158474682814198297?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Entelechy and a Burlesque Frame</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/entelechy-and-a-burlesque-frame.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-06T18:58:45Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-06T18:58:45Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/entelechy-and-a-burlesque-frame.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;I was not sure if I was behind a blog or not so I thought I would take this opportunity to discuss a very complicated article (self assigned), I am reading for my research project in History 373. The article is cited as&amp;nbsp;follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hubbard, Bryan(1998) &amp;#8216;Reassessing Truman, the bomb, and revisionism: The burlesque frame and entelechy in the decision to use atomic weapons against Japan&amp;#8217;, Western Journal of Communication, 62: 3, 348 —&amp;nbsp;385.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Is there anything in the title that seems a little complicated? “Burlesque frame” in reference to the use of atomic weapons; and in case you missed it, “entelechy.” When I read that I thought I had mistakenly click on something from the History 307 reading list. I looked up entelechy and got the best definition from Britannica, which said, “in philosophy, that which realizes or makes actual what is otherwise merely potential.” Now that I know what it means, I definitely know that as a historian I would want to avoid it.  I have been reading articles on Truman’s decision to use the bomb on Japan and was unable to put to words what some of the revisionists have been using as proof until I came to understand entelechy.  For example, Gar Alperovitz (big critic of the Truman decision) wrote about Japanese peace overtures to the &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;USSR&lt;/span&gt; as if they were in fact peace overtures to all. I wanted to criticize that in my paper but lacked the vocabulary to make a clean attack.  Later, Hubbard titles a section, “Burlesque Frame: The Missing Context of Revisionist Re-readings,” and I thought “context is everything.” If you are still reading this post you deserve an explanation of the burlesque frame. Hubbard (credited to Burke) utilizes this particular “rhetorical frame” to provide a context that is the “mirror image” of the intuitive war frame of tragedy. The use of the Burlesque or comedic frame means that you avoid identifying with the victims of war so you do not lose your objectivity. This works because the actors in the Burlesque are absurd and do not garner pity. That frame helps us as historians, but Hubbard also writes that because the parties in war dehumanize their victims as means to accomplish their goals, that the Burlesque Frame is the most proper wartime context. Hubbard also used entelechy as the momentum behind the decision in his own analysis of Truman’s decision. This article was a nice piece of historiography which analyzed the debate and versions over what some believe to be the biggest historical event of the 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/39/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=39&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Timeline vs. Metaphor</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/timeline-vs-metaphor.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-05T04:44:20Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-05T04:44:20Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/timeline-vs-metaphor.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This past week we read &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Invading Guatemala: Spanish, Nahua, and Maya Accounts of the Conquest Wars&lt;/span&gt; written by Matthew Restall and Florine Asselbergs. The title is description enough, as the book presents and analyzes various first hand accounts of the conquest of Guatemala. We analyzed the third letter from Pedro Alvarado to Hernando Cortés and attempted to reconstruct a timeline and analyze the &amp;#8220;literal&amp;#8221; facts and also examined the use of metaphors within the letter.  After class I applied similar tactics to Bernal Díaz&amp;#8217;s account of Pedro&amp;#8217;s conquest of Guatemala and it was very interesting corroborating the details as well as analyzing the piece with some new historical skill. Díaz was also a conquistador in the region but arrived later than Alvarado and did not participate in all of his conquests. The tone of his account is similar to that of Pedro&amp;#8217;s as he clearly views the natives as less civilized and their towns as &amp;#8220;unsettled&amp;#8221;. When searching the piece for metaphor, one realizes that Díaz characterizes the native societies according to the structures of his own, exactly as Pedro Alvarado does in his letter. The employment of metaphors such a town, city, fort, province, and region are all examples of this organization according to Spanish conceptions of society. While the metaphors employed paralleled Alvarado&amp;#8217;s letter, so did the factual evidence. Events such as coming across a sacrificed dog and woman, mountain pass battles, the burning of town leaders, and the peacemaking efforts are present in both reports. The validation of such information is exciting, but one also must take into account Díaz&amp;#8217;s sources, of which I am unaware. Even looking at the map and making a timeline, I found it difficult to directly tie the dates together even though they have similar chronicles. I found this exercise in class to be very stimulating and informative, and doing it out of class built my confidence and kindled my historical&amp;nbsp;interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/31/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=31&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Gonzalo de Alvarado</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/gonzalo-de-alvarado.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-05T03:17:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-05T03:17:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/gonzalo-de-alvarado.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Invading Guatemala&lt;/i&gt; by Matthew Restall and Florine Asselbergs provides us with a great example of how historical interpretation can rarely be justified through the use of a single primary document. &amp;nbsp;As evidence, consider the inaccurate scholarship prior to 2004 that juxtaposed Pedro de Alvarado as the primary conqueror of Guatemala. &amp;nbsp;If a historian were to construct his record of the events based solely on the accounts provided by Pedro, it would certainly be a limited work, positioning that he himself was responsible for the conquering and subsequent colonization. &amp;nbsp;However, when one reviews the letters provided by Pedro, Gonzalo, Jorge, and the Nahua/Maya accounts it becomes easy to see that many people were involved in the conquest, some even more so than Pedro himself.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The testimony provided by Pedro&amp;#8217;s cousin Gonzalo de Alvarado, whom joined his campaign in 1524, gives insight into an alternative dimension of the Guatemalan conquest. &amp;nbsp;As it were, Gonzalo&amp;#8217;s writings originated as petitions to the King of Spain asking for retribution in light of his extensive work within Guatemala. &amp;nbsp;This institutional context has enormous consequences on the author&amp;#8217;s mindset, tone, and overall flow of the piece. &amp;nbsp;For example, Pedro Alvarado&amp;#8217;s letters like to emphasize the successes of the Guatemalan conquest in order to influence Pedro&amp;#8217;s perceived image by Cortes, the Spanish King, and the larger Spanish populace. &amp;nbsp;On the other hand, Gonzalo Alvarado&amp;#8217;s petition emphasizes the enormity of personal risk and subsequent losses by the Spanish conquistador. &amp;nbsp;Gonzalo&amp;#8217;s rhetoric often makes the reader believe that only through amazing perseverance and luck did the conquering company manage to survive. &amp;nbsp;Additionally, unlike his cousin Jorge, Gonzalo seems to support the idea that Pedro Alvarado was the main actor in Guatemala&amp;#8217;s conquest. &amp;nbsp;This is most likely due to the fact that Gonzalo wanted to exaggerate Pedro&amp;#8217;s accomplishments, hoping the King would readily give pension/money to a close associate of the great conqueror. &amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Within a discursive analysis of Gonzalo&amp;#8217;s letter, it proves exceptionally hard to follow any sensible chronological framework. &amp;nbsp;However, here is my attempt at formulating a timeline of Gonzalo&amp;#8217;s travels:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Set-up: Gonzalo joins Pedro on his way to Guatemala and Cuzcatan.&lt;br /&gt;Day 1: Gonzalo and company defend themselves against warriors at entrance to Capotitlan.&lt;br /&gt;Day 2: Gonzalo and company arrive at Capotitlan and battle many fierce warriors.&lt;br /&gt;Day 2 (night): Gonzalo and company take arrow bombardment from enemies.&lt;br /&gt;Day 4: Company arrives in the town of Quezaltenango.&lt;br /&gt;Day 7: Ten thousand Indians gather to wage war against conquerors. &amp;nbsp;Pedro attempts to offer peace, but messengers are rejected.&lt;br /&gt;Day 8: &amp;nbsp;War in the town of Quezaltenango.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: (Some days after aforementioned battle): Company arrives in province of Utatlan.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: Company arrives in Guatemala and set out to pacify Cuzcatlan.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: (Many days after conquest of Cuzcatlan): Company returns to Guatemala and sets out in search of the &amp;#8220;North Sea.&amp;#8221;&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: &amp;#8220;Having walked for many days,&amp;#8221; the company reaches an impasse and must look for an alternative route home.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: After many days, Gonzalo finds a road leading to Tecpan Puyumatlan. &lt;br /&gt;Day ?: The company is attacked numerous times while travelling through Tecpan Puyumatlan province.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: After many days, the company must return to Guatemala due to lack of food and supplies.&lt;br /&gt;Day ?: Lastly, Gonzalo delves into a generalized description of the six year uprisings and subsequent hardships he faced.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;As you can see, it is almost impossible to create any sort of informative timeline based solely on Gonzalo&amp;#8217;s testimony as he rarely provides approximate dates.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;One other thing I wanted to note from discussion last week was about the seven myths of Spanish-American conquest. &amp;nbsp;I feel like at one time or another over the past 15 years of schooling I have been taught all of the &amp;#8216;myths&amp;#8217; as &amp;#8216;facts&amp;#8217;. &amp;nbsp;Weren&amp;#8217;t we all taught that &lt;i&gt;white&lt;/i&gt; conquistadors were originally believed to be &amp;#8216;white gods&amp;#8217; by the semi-unified native resistance? &amp;nbsp;It really makes me wonder what other histories I have an inaccurate or incomplete view of&amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-8949690136171291984?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Invading Guatemala</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/invading-guatemala.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-04T18:08:39Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-04T18:08:39Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/invading-guatemala.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;The account of Bernal Diaz Castillo in &lt;em&gt;Invading Guatemala, &lt;/em&gt;(page 61-69)&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;bordered on ridiculous. That being said, there were portions of the account which could be of use. First, some of the comical, like “Pedro Alvarado went to the province of Guatemala to found a town, and bring them peace.” For some reason that reminded of Ronald Reagan naming a ballistic nuclear missile, “The Peacemaker,” but I digress. Castillo also wrote about “cages that held Indians until they were fat enough to eat.” After the long climb to the top of the pass Castillo claims a force of six thousand attacked, while Alvarado (already known for inflating enemy strength) only reported three or four thousand. The end of the Castillo account said, “they were not fighters because they only lay in wait for us in the gorges, and shot at us with their arrows.” This combined with other statements about the ease by which they “made peace” (conquered the enemy) indicates a complete lack of respect for the enemy. I found this curious because it has the effect of diminishing the alleged victory because the opponent is unworthy.  In 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; Century North America we see the development of the noble savage, a “worthy” opponent, as a means to aggrandize ones on accomplishments in&amp;nbsp;battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The limited value of the Castillo account can be found in the similarities with other versions; and as we discussed in class it can help to establish a timeline. He also mentioned the dead woman and dog reportedly a sacrifice, but Castillo did not indicate that it was a warning. That part of this story is a mysterious little detail, but it is clear by its very mention, that it had an effect on the Spaniards. When a source is so clearly biased it almost makes it easier to gain value from his/her writings because you do not need to determine the bias and you can set aside the information which is clearly prejudicial, like cannibalism.  Good book very useful for comparative analysis of an event with multiple sources. Talk to you next&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/37/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=37&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Jorge de Alvarado</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/jorge-de-alvarado.html"/>
            <updated>2011-04-02T18:38:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-04-02T18:38:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/jorge-de-alvarado.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Jorge de Alvarado’s account&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Pg. 55-59&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;His account presents a differing point of view than his cousin Gonzalo de Alvarado. He discusses his campaign of 1527 to 1529 in which led to the Spanish colony in Guatemala. This letter was to the King, written on February 26, 1534. This letter is asking for the King of Spain to make Jorge de Alvarado the governor of the provinces of Guatemala that he states he conquered and pacified. Alvarado uses many routes to show how he deserves this appointment especially over his brother. He first tries to correct the wrongdoing that has occurred in the credit of the conquering of Guatemala. He does this by explaining how he was actually the one to conquer and pacify the land. He then explains how he did this with much personal expense to himself. He also is very careful to show that this conquering was not a simple task, but came at much personal hardship. He explains how they did not just walk away easily but had to be very persistent with the natives. He uses rhetoric that makes sure to sound that he is the only one that was ever able to pacify Guatemala. That no one had been able to do it before, and he went in heroically and saved the day. It is also very evident that Jorge is writing persuasively to the king. He uses vocabulary that evokes his honoring and humbleness to the king. He says “Your Holy Majesty” and “kisses your royal feet.” The reader can feel his desperation to receive what he deserves is his. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The letter comes at a very important time in both the lives of Pedro and Jorge de Alvarado. Pedro would come back from his expedition from Peru in a year. Jorge knew that he had a very small window to explain to the king why Pedro should not receive the governorship at his return. He wanted to explain everything he had been able to do in Pedro’s absence. But, he also knew that the state of Guatemala on his arrival in 1527 would not be known to anyone but himself. This was the weakness of his letter is that to a King half a world away, it could not be explained the depth of the change that Jorge had on Guatemala. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This letter is very important for the historical interpretation of the conquering of Guatemala. Before 2004 it was an ingrained fact that Pedro de Alvarado was the conqueror and settler of Guatemala. But, through the publication of the Jorge’s letter in 2004 it helped to explain his side of the story. This version is also very important because this is the first time it is being published in English. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Because of the context this source is very important for not just verifying to the King who is responsible for conquering Guatemala, but also to history. Jorge had insight and was able to see that his brother once returned would receive credit for what he had done. He wrote this letter to first receive politically what he felt he deserved but also historically. Unfortunately, because of Pedro’s connections he was able to leave history with a more impactful legacy. This source is incredibly important to unearthing what the true history of the conquering of Guatemala was. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;o:p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Till next week,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-6498238354871906723?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Agility in history?</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/agility-in-history.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-30T01:58:50Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-30T01:58:50Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/agility-in-history.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;First off, the observer in the room made me quite nervous. Now that that&amp;#8217;s out of the way, I enjoyed the addition to our Historian&amp;#8217;s Recipe Book. Agility is a key factor in us understanding and analyzing our primary and secondary sources. Without agility, our research would be at a snail&amp;#8217;s pace and there would not be much information gained. By not analyzing the different methods present and using different lenses one is left with a shallow interpretation. The difference between sources and remains was discussed and these definitions provoke thought concerning the author&amp;#8217;s intent and unintentional windows into the past. We then went over Hermaneutics and discourse analysis as competing methods and stressed agility between the two. Hermaneutics stresses the analysis of the reality portrayed by text while discourse analysis argues that text constitutes reality, and is not limited by&amp;nbsp;text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then split into groups and I had my say about the analysis of letters as a primary source. The primary point raised by the book seemed to be the difference between public and private letters. Once again a simple concept, but one wholly necessary to the interpretation of this primary source. This difference concerns the audience and the author also states that letters are never a solitary act. The writer is aware of their audience, what they expect, and the structures of society. The author of the book also warns the historian that these writers often shape their own reality as opposed to the objective truth. A letter from a Soviet citizen to a government official in 1953 is then examined(pg.66-67). The conclusions drawn and question raised from this article are striking. What a professional historian gains from two paragraphs causes a sense of respect and envy within&amp;nbsp;me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book mentioned in this post is &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Reading Primary Sources&lt;/span&gt; edited by Dobson and&amp;nbsp;Ziemann.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=28&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Just a thought....</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/just-a-thought.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-29T03:42:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-29T03:42:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/just-a-thought.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;For my blog this week I am going to stray away from the norm of describing what we have discussed in class and making commentary on it. Instead I would like to talk about what I took from the reading last week. I will first give a little insight into my thoughts on the Remains vs. sources debate but I would like to go into other items that I took from “Reading Primary Sources.” Firstly, I think it would be very hard if in research you were stuck strictly with sources. If that were your area of study such as intellectual history that we discussed in class it would be very efficient. But, in my mind it could cloud the factual history that we are trying to construct. But, on the other hand just because a primary document is found that was never intended to be read does not mean it is not void of biases. But, maybe even further what is important is that whether it is remains or a source when reading the primary source we can take away what the perspective was at that time pertaining what we are researching. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“For him, disclosing the historical ideas behind past events enabled one to develop a sense of the general structure of history.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;One interesting part in part 1 that contrasted with Droysen’s theories on remains and sources was Ranke’s theories on historical criticism. He believed that the true facts of history could only come by a historian using intensive assessment of the historical sources. Through this historians can detect historical changes and the subjective becomes the objective. What became most important about this section was neither Ranke or Droysen but the fact that by accepting the usefulness of constructing past events through primary documents it meant a huge change in historiography. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;When reading the sections that concerned different types of primary documents different ways that certain kinds of documents could become useful occurred to me. During the letter section of the book one of the most interesting parts was how letters can reveal characteristics about people that without the document would become unknown. One example of this demographic is the poor and powerless. As more people became literate more people wrote letters that expressed their views on their situations. These letters could reveal much to a person researching. I think another very important part of the letter section that had never occurred to me was letters of citizenship. One letter that has been used from Ken Burns to Douglass Southall Freeman is the story of a girl who sent a letter to Abraham Lincoln telling him to grow a beard so that he could win the election. This is a very famous letter that shows the love of Lincoln that this little girl inhibits. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In the memoranda section there was a concept that I would like to dwell on that I am wondering if could be used in other areas of primary document and that is the concept of a ‘think piece.’ This idea is to say that they are studying a political decision and find a memo that would have been the turning point of that decision. Now this would be very hard to find but it is out there. This is the point of studying memoranda is to find out the complexities of the backgrounds of the political decisions that were made. Maybe the decision is not what it seems on the surface. There could be clues about the aggression of the decision. I am wondering if this could be found in letters and diaries. Maybe there is a think piece in a diary that explains why a person made the decision they did. Just an insight. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-7873707520287990142?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Primary Sources</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/primary-sources.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-29T02:30:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-29T02:30:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/primary-sources.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; So I thought I would write a bit about each of the chapters I read on primary sources for this past week: letters, newspapers, and court files. &amp;nbsp;First off, court files document by what standards people in the past were judged and how people interacted with these standards. &amp;nbsp;As an historian, when working with court files it is important to recognize that they contain a multiplicity of content (i.e. interrogations, testimonies, verdicts). &amp;nbsp;While this certainly gives the researcher a plethora of potential information, often the varying accounts can be riddled with conscious distortions of the truth. &amp;nbsp;Beyond this, the book lays out three key concepts to consider when using court files as primary sources. &amp;nbsp;First, one must remember the dialogical nature of court files &amp;#8212; usually the documents are a compilation of multiple perspectives. &amp;nbsp;Moreover, it is critical to consider the files&amp;#8217; emplotment: under what circumstances led to the court files&amp;#8217; creation? &amp;nbsp;Lastly, the nature of court files presupposes an underlying cultural context, as one can catch a glimpse of what people in the past considered normal behavior. &amp;nbsp;Working with Constitutionalism as a topic I feel like I will be reading many, many court files as I move forward. &amp;nbsp;In fact, the article I read for the paper on methodology employed court files successfully in showing how certain cases increased the government’s role within the American economy, albeit Constitutional limitations.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The next primary source I read about was newspapers, as I unintelligibly discussed in class. &amp;nbsp;Newspapers are distinguishable sources largely because they filter through raw news and cover only the most contemporary issues. &amp;nbsp;Additionally, newspapers stand out as a source because they rely on paid advertisements to survive, providing advertisers with de facto licensing power. &amp;nbsp;Clearly, one has to consider this along with other elements of the paper&amp;#8217;s institutional framework to determine if newspapers are source-worthy. &amp;nbsp;For instance, who really controls the paper: the editorial staff or the paying advertisers? &amp;nbsp;Another factor to reflect on is the visual context and overall editorial decisions that contributed to the newspapers&amp;#8217; production. &amp;nbsp;It makes quite a bit of difference in knowing whether an article was a front page piece or simply shoved somewhere along the inner pages of the newspaper. &amp;nbsp;Lastly, a potential researcher would also want to review the textual context of the piece. &amp;nbsp;At times the author&amp;#8217;s tone, narrative voice, and sources used can help you determine if the newspaper is a credible source. &amp;nbsp;Clearly, newspapers are a tricky source to use effectively as they can be hard to analyze and have a great many prospective downfalls.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Last but not least I also wanted to read the section covering letters as primary sources. &amp;nbsp;As the book discusses briefly, it is interesting to contemplate how the use of letters in writing great man history was a precursor to its extensive use in writing histories from below. &amp;nbsp;Letter writing is a relational process as one learns about both the author and the intended reader in accessing the personal life of the correspondents. &amp;nbsp;However, personal letters exist alongside more official letters, perhaps between a citizen and their governing body. &amp;nbsp;Obviously I feel like I would be working more with official letters while composing a political history versus a social one. &amp;nbsp;There are a few things that affect the way a letter writer articulates his/her thoughts, slightly limiting the reader&amp;#8217;s window into the author&amp;#8217;s views. &amp;nbsp;For one, conventions of letter writing constrain the author into pre-conceived formalities of letter composition. &amp;nbsp;Moreover, the authors words are molded by what they think the letter recipient expects. &amp;nbsp;However, in the end it seemed to me like the book offered letters as one of the better sources, at least in evaluating the mindset of an individual author.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;On another note, I love the sheer amount of directories provided by&lt;i&gt; The Information-Literate Historian&lt;/i&gt;. &amp;nbsp;I&amp;#8217;ve played around on a couple of the government documents directories, but didn&amp;#8217;t spend enough time on them to find anything too cool..&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-5045879521729698138?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Reading Primary Sources</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/reading-primary-sources.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-28T17:37:46Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-28T17:37:46Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/reading-primary-sources.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This week’s assignment, “Reading Primary Sources” a multiple author compilation edited by Miriam Dobson (she is a girl) and Benjamin Ziemann (boy), was my favorite so far because out of all the prior readings this one seemed the most practical and useful of the lot.  I understand that is by design at this point in the semester, but it is nice to transition away from theory and passed (pun intended) historians.  I know we still had some dead Germans to talk about but part &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; was a great “how to guide” on a variety of sources, all of which I have decided can be called e-mail.  I wanted to discuss the two chapters I did not have time to discuss in class. Beyond diaries, I chose opinion polls and testimony. I have always heard that opinion polls can be manipulated to mean or say whatever you like, but I never thought about how they can be used to manipulate public opinion. When the media reports a poll “like it is science” the result can begin to sway the public in the direction previously reported in the poll.  See, we are a trendy species and at times can allow our minds to be changed on issues based on their perceived popularity.  Polls are not without value however, aside from the straight line results of the poll, they can tell us a lot about the mood of a past society based on the poll questions. For example, a future study on our society will be able to discern that abortion was a major topic for our time based on the amount of polls on the&amp;nbsp;subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of abortion, Leslie Reagan’s “When Abortion was a Crime” taught us the value of testimony(see my 2/5/11 post). In “Reading Primary Sources,” the Testimony section was written by Devin Pendas who said, “testimony can answer some questions very well and others not at all.” That is because trial testimony by design tends to focus on a specific and narrow topic, like an alleged crime. That is what made Leslie Reagan’s research so impressive because she gained knowledge based on the unspoken in the testimony. Pendas demonstrates the difficulty in “who to believe” in opposing testimonies, with Nazi guard/Holocaust survivor testimonies. Very compelling testimony and the truth is not as apparent as one might think.  I highly recommend the chapter on testimony. This is a book I will keep and use in the future.  More next week, if I survive my mother-in-laws five day visit this&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/35/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=35&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Methodology 2 Week 9</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/methodology-2-week-9.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-11T01:57:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-11T01:57:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/methodology-2-week-9.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Merriam Webster defines a method as “a procedure or process for attaining an object.” Before this week it was very hard to see how we take use the steps involved in methodology and form them into a coherent argument; even further into a finished product of a paper. This week the concepts of methodology were put into a coherent set of steps. Through this process the object of creating a paper can be accomplished. Any of the pieces seperatly do not result in a solid paper, but all together they do. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In the two articles that I read for this week they were both done through a local approach. The first article by Sundiata Cha-Jua was about the northern town of Decatur, Illinois from 1894 to 1898. She is making an argument about the situation of lynching and racial mob violence throughout the north by concentrating on this small town. By discussing the events in the town of Decatur the author makes a statement about the racial problems in small towns while at the same time discussing it on a national level. This article sets itself apart from the other because it uses the local aspect to go along with what is going on nationally. She is also able through her article to understand why some lynching’s were prevented by a mob of African-Americans and some were not. The first lynching she discusses of Samuel J. Bush was not prevented because he was not a local. He had just been passing through. Also this was a town that had not seen much racial violence if any so the fact that a man was being lynched was very strange. The second potential lynching of James Jackson was stopped by a mob that made sure he was protected. Another characteristic part of the article was the author’s use of secondary source concepts that help to define the terms of what was going on in this small town. One example of this is Craig Calhoun’s concept of community, density, and multiplicity. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The second article was much different because it did not mention anything at a global level at all. But, by talking in depth on a local level the author is also making a statement about the global world also. In class we learned that there can be terms other than global and local. There is the individual speaking generally about a group. This article uses this a lot because it goes in depth about certain individuals to speak generally about a whole group. This article by Sharon Farmer is speaking about the population of immigrants to the town of St Dennis and their use of the tomb of Louis &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;IX&lt;/span&gt; who was soon-to-be canonized. The source is very significant because it is taken from one set of stories from the &lt;i style=&#34;mso-bidi-font-style: normal;&#34;&gt;Miracle of Saint Louis&lt;/i&gt;. The author speaks specifically about the women and their individual agency. She makes a line between women who are married and women who are single. Because it has been thought that the women who are married had more advantages. But, they actually did not. If they were sick they were forced to beg on the streets, while still caring for their famalies. But, what is significant is the towns the sense of community that was created. Neighbors would go to help women who they had heard were healed. Also, if a single woman was in need there were women who could help her. The other part of the article that is significant is her use of microhistory. This was a term that I was not familiar with. Through her use of this one source she is able to make an assessment of women’s lives who are on the bottom of society. Further making an argument for all immigrant women in Paris and throughout the country. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-2365194936396144550?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Historian’s Recipe Book</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/historiane28099s-recipe-book.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-08T20:52:26Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-08T20:52:26Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/historiane28099s-recipe-book.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;We have moved from the realm of historiography into that of historical methods, and while it would have been nice to receive a history cookbook from Dr. Black, I am glad we have moved into a more concrete realm of developing our skills. We ran with the metaphor of becoming a chef and this really helped my understanding the process of becoming a professional historian. From there we examined three key points regarding methodology. The first was that context matters above all else. When examining a historical document, we must consider several factors including time period, intended audience, position of the author, and structures present in which the source was produced. All of these have effects upon the evidence, whether they were intended or not. The second point is that language is not transparent. Through time, words change meaning and documents will thusly be read differently. As long as the historian recognizes these first two points (s)he is on the way to an objective piece. For me, this related back to the refutation of the &amp;#8220;prison house&amp;#8221; of language in the previous book. The authors dismissed the disjunction of reality and truth by clearly stating that these two aforementioned points  are present in most true historians&amp;#8217; methods. The third point seemed obvious but finding appropriate sources is the start of any historian&amp;#8217;s work and must be done with diligence and a discerning&amp;nbsp;eye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the discussion of methods we examined the history of ethnohistory and how its definition has evolved. This was interesting because initially  it concerned &amp;#8220;primitive&amp;#8221; peoples, mainly those not being in the white majority of these historians. The definition then transformed into a very specific statement and ended up being broader than the first one. As we were running out of time we brought up the piece that researched orphanages in Sevilla and applied its findings to children in colonial Latin America and the early modern Iberian Peninsula. This is clearly a piece of ethnohistory and the historian&amp;#8217;s method of examining new documents allowed a richer, more objective history. She explained the social stratification within these orphanages and even the difference between orphans and foundlings. She concluded that people took advantage of these institutions in order to better provide for their children, a very interesting observation.&lt;br /&gt;
While learning the methodology is exciting, I envy historians&amp;#8217; minds who process this information&amp;nbsp;automatically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/24/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=24&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Methodology Week 8</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/methodology-week-8.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-08T04:07:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-08T04:07:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/methodology-week-8.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“Historical methodology, as I see it, is a product of common sense applied to circumstances.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This week I took a step back and decided to investigate where I get my information from. I decided to really watch if I get information from the Internet. It turns out I get a lot more from the Internet than I even thought. It may not seem like receiving information but the H-Net emails I receive information from to the Public History news I look up are all receiving information. I also tend to look at the news in a one sided way. So I have decided to try and make myself more informed on an unbiased way. But, as we have learned in this class this is harder than it seems. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Methodology is defined as a set or system of methods, principles, and rules for regulating a given discipline, as in the arts or sciences. Methodology is one of the hardest terms that we have to define. Historical methodology is the guidelines by which historians use primary resources and research to form their papers. In class we talked about what makes up this complicated term. The best way to understand why and how historians form this was through the example in class of what makes historians. How it is a training process. One of the most important parts of this was the language and how when reading a primary document it should be not be transparent. It should not be something that is looked over. The language that is used can give an insight to the reader about the time and the way that they viewed what was going on. In class we talked about how hermeneutics played into this. When using hermeneutics the reader is able to define the intent of the document to its most basic intent. The reader is able to see how the document would have been able to be read at the time. This is very important when doing research and basing an argument on this. Because if you do research and base the subject of your argument on documents. Then if you do not understand the point of the document than your argument will be lost. You may totally miss what the writer of the document was trying to say. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;mso-spacerun: yes;&#34;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;I feel this is when ethnohistory becomes so important. Even when using oral histories, which are so important to this method of history, you have to put yourself into that situation. Saying that language is not transparent is the same thing as saying that culture is not transparent. If you look over a culture and just compare it to whatever is familiar to you, than you will lose the complete reason for the ethnohistory. That is why it was so hard for them to define because until the late 1980s early 1990s this ethnocentrism could not be shaken off. That is why personal views play so much into history. True ethnohistory could not be done until the shackles of the past ignorance had been shaken. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In the article written by Valentina Tikoff, she had to put herself in the time and read the situation differently than it had before. The situation at the orphanages had only been read through the court documents. But now she was reading the registers for orphanages. By doing this she had to learn the language and the vocabulary of what would be in there. She also had to explain this in her writing so that her argument would be even stronger. She had to explain the difference between a Foundling and an orphan. She also had to be able to explain the different kind of orphans that were there. To explain the people that was paying to go there. By using methodology she was able to do this and her argument that orphanages were not just being used in the literal sense.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-3344104306990503024?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Context Matters</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/context-matters.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-06T22:53:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-06T22:53:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/context-matters.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The article on ethnohistory by Russell Barber and Frances Berdan wasn&amp;#8217;t the first time I had been introduced to the idea, but it was certainly helpful to analyze the authors&amp;#8217; attempts to conceptualize the study of ethnohistory. &amp;nbsp;One might think the task impossible after the failures of the &lt;i&gt;Ethnohistory&lt;/i&gt; journal to establish a simple, yet fully encompassing mission statement. &amp;nbsp;However, the authors of the article spend less time worrying about formal definitions and more time focusing on how ethnohistory is defined by actions. &amp;nbsp;These actions include the research, scholarly output, and methodological approaches manipulated by the common ethnohistorian. &amp;nbsp;In fact, the author spends considerable time discussing the assumptions and approaches that combine to establish an interpretative framework by which the ethnohistorian constructs their work. &amp;nbsp;In many instances assumptions and approaches can be understood as dichotomies. &amp;nbsp;Take for example the differences in methodologies as represented between emic vs. etic / particularist vs. nomothetic / single-factor vs. multi-factor. &amp;nbsp;The decisions ethnohistorians make about which approaches to use can be largely extrapolated to most other scholarly discourses. &amp;nbsp;When assessing a primary document or generally conducting any kind of research, it&amp;#8217;s crucial to employ a wide variety of appropriate methodological approaches. There is not a formula for applying these methodologies, nor any set of guidelines. &amp;nbsp;In reality, the methodological approaches one uses can and most likely should change as you move from topic to topic or source to source. &amp;nbsp;In part, recognizing an author&amp;#8217;s methodology plays into the idea of &amp;#8216;deconstruction&amp;#8217;, the act of identifying an author&amp;#8217;s general mindset and how it shapes a resultant document. &amp;nbsp;As we derived in class, context matters above all else.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The other two articles were interesting in the ways they approached their objects of research: the capital case files held by Canada&amp;#8217;s national archive in one and the records generated by the orphanages of Seville in the other. &amp;nbsp;For example, the authors of &lt;i&gt;On the Case: Explorations in Social History&lt;/i&gt; recognized the complexity of power dynamics that was inherent in the context of bureaucratic case files. &amp;nbsp;In fact, the authors imbue that the reader must understand a case file&amp;#8217;s original purpose, nature, and structure. &amp;nbsp;In other words, the contexts that the case files were established in matters beyond all else. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-351906521831904582?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Reality Mediation</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/reality-mediation.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-06T20:15:08Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-06T20:15:08Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/reality-mediation.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;The readings every week seem to do a good job of putting words to concepts that once revealed seem obvious. This weeks readings were interesting, particularly the &lt;em&gt;Emperors Mirror&lt;/em&gt; and the discussion on Reality Mediation.  The authors, Russell J. Barber and Frances F. Berdan discuss the difference between a historians description and reality.  We may intuitively believe that our description is the same as reality but if you think about it you realize that, like 100% objectivity, you can never completely capture the reality of a past event no matter how reliable your primary sources and observer of the event happen to be; but if we understand four ways to mediate that reality then we can write a more accurate description. The first is selection, what portions of a reality are left out. We need to be conscious of what does not make our description and why. This analysis might prevent us from overlooking a key aspect of our primary source. The next is emphasis; once something makes it into our description which sections receive more emphasis and why. The third is transformation; something was selected then modified.  Make sure you understand first that it was modified and then again ask why. The last notion is fabrication; beware of the source that is not telling the truth. (Barber and Berdan, 39.) The authors provided the example of Champlain&amp;#8217;s description of an exotic bird sighting used to explain a detour in his journey.  It is suspected that he made up the bird to cover for being lost.  This piece of information might useful in a way other than rare North American Ornithological studies, it might for example refute the notion that Champlain never got&amp;nbsp;lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By using what seem to be obvious concepts we can utilize this process of Reality Mediation to attempt to produce the most accurate description of events&amp;nbsp;possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/32/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=32&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">History does not exist in a vacuum</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/history-does-not-exist-in-a-vacuum.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-02T04:03:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-02T04:03:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/history-does-not-exist-in-a-vacuum.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;“History does not exist in a vacuum.”&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;These insightful words were spoken to me just this past weekend. I felt that they applied to our discussion from class very well. I am going to take a personal moment for a second at the risk of annoying the reader and the general audience of our small class. This past weekend I went to a Civil War Conference. During one of the lectures he was speaking about &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;JEB&lt;/span&gt; Stuart, a personal favorite of mine, he was speaking about how so much of what we know of him is skewed because of what was written after the war. To elaborate his point he said, “history is not what is told by the people who lived it, but what we write it to be.” For me this was a light bulb moment for everything we have discussed in class. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Now to actually discuss the reading from last week. The basis that the three authors begin their book with is the replacement of a scientific outlook of history from a religious. They emphasize how before the eighteenth century religion dominated the shaping of history. Through historians using a scientific outlook and shedding this closer minded idea of history they were able to shed the first layer of objectivity. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Through the gaining of strength of these scientists they became heroes. The last part of this is the rise of nationalism. It cannot be exactly described the change from kingdoms to nations. How this had an effect on how people not just saw their nations but also their individual selves. All of these innovations were considered in the author’s banner of Historical Absolutism. This term although very tricky really does sum up this way of history that existed. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The way America shaped this history is even deeper. “At the center, then, of American history was an under socialized, individualistic, concept of human nature set in an over determined story of progress (125).” America’s deepest struggles were only understood on the surface level. This reminded me of a concept that was developed relatively recently by the Southern Historical Scholar Edward Ayers, concerning the Civil War. To counteract the idea that individual people do not play a role in struggles he came up with the idea of Deep Contingency. Deep contingency is that large and individual people’s arguments play a larger role in the eventual conflict; plural and singular events play in and effect everyday people’s lives. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This book by Joyce Appleby, Lynn Hunt, and Margaret Jacob were very effective in placing the study of history in a larger context. It connected many of the dots previously not connected. Our history will always be colored by where and when we are. But, the goal is not to give up our of frustration but to keep searching for the truth. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-7094217524950848041?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">The Truth</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/the-truth.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-01T05:13:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-01T05:13:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/the-truth.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Telling the Truth about History&lt;/i&gt; imbues upon its readers an understanding of the development of history as a discipline, investigating the various ways in which historians have traditionally surveyed the past. &amp;nbsp;It seems that the early history of history itself was restricted in scope by non-conformative absolutisms. &amp;nbsp;At first, most intellectual pursuits were performed in light of religion, as most correlated religion with the be-all, end-all truth. &amp;nbsp;During the 18th century and beginning within the framework of the Enlightenment, the authors recognize the advent of science as the pedestal for which all truths were founded. &amp;nbsp;Unfortunately, the enlightened enemies of religious absolutism created an absolutism of their own, one based around this scientific history and subsequent modernity. &amp;nbsp;In this methodological absolutism, scientists wielded a large bastion of power as they were thought of as those closest in contact with the objective truths of reality (grand schemas organizing all knowledge into a uniform body). &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; After the devastation of World War &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; and the advent of the atomic bomb, science lost most of its glamour. &amp;nbsp;How was science supposed to be value-free, neutral, and a path leading to a greater understanding of humanity, when it had invariably led to such destruction? &amp;nbsp;From this starting point, opponents of modernity began their assault against it. &amp;nbsp;The heavy critique of modernity that has developed in the last half century has been the focus of &amp;#8216;postmodernists&amp;#8217;. &amp;nbsp;According to the author, postmodernism&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;primary goal has been to challenge convictions about objectivity of knowledge and the stability of language&amp;#8221; (pg. 201). &amp;nbsp;As it were, postmodernists challenge the idea that an all-encompassing, objective truth can be accessible, at least not one which would create overlaying organizational schemas of knowledge. &amp;nbsp;I didn&amp;#8217;t fully understand the postmodern convictions against language as well as its convictions against objectivity. &amp;nbsp;I think postmodernists hold that words don&amp;#8217;t correspond to reality, only other words, insofar that reality is simply the creature of language?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; In the end, I feel like the authors make a convincing case for practical pragmatism and against all-out relativism. &amp;nbsp;In essence, it is essential for historians to recognize and move beyond these constricting methodologies of interpreting the past. &amp;nbsp;Additionally, the historian must recognize his/her own limitations in grasping only a part of the actual historical truth. &amp;nbsp;Yet, this relativistic view does not necessarily spell doom for the historian in his/her search for objectivity. &amp;nbsp;In fact, a grander and more objective reality can be ascertained primarily through the mingling of various interpretations originating from differing perspectives. &amp;nbsp;Within an ever-changing democratic society, it is crucial for all knowledge to flow interchangeably between society and individual - hopefully establishing the objective truths all historians seek.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;See you guys later this week.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-8861362566308812579?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Telling the Truth About History</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth-about-history.html"/>
            <updated>2011-03-01T04:47:46Z</updated>
            <published>2011-03-01T04:47:46Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth-about-history.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;First off, this book was written by three women and not one man. Now that this tricky piece of information is out of the way, the piece can be discussed. The concept this book addresses seems to be the influence of certain periods upon historiography and how the ideals developed are eventually toppled and replaced. The first example of this progression in the dismissal of theological reasoning with the rise of the Enlightenment, and secularism pervaded the realm of academia. As national identities began to take root and influence history, they were then stripped down through the examination of various historical accounts of a nation. Science was then removed from its pedestal after the examination of social conditioning upon scientific research i.e. the influence of newly developed social theory upon Darwin&amp;#8217;s theory of natural selection. The next chapter deals with the postmodernist&amp;#8217;s attack upon the narrative of history and the individual in general. In all honesty, the subject of postmodernity piques my intellectual interests, especially regarding the prison of language, but its implications are not the most appealing. The authors come to the conclusion that the gap between reality and its narration does not render history and an individual&amp;#8217;s narration of it unsound, rather they urge the formation of new historical methods for the future, which clearly applies to our position as students of&amp;nbsp;history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/20/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=20&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Telling the truth?</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-28T03:23:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-28T03:23:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Telling the Truth About History is a somewhat ironic title for this book, for one of the central questions it raises is whether it is even possible to achieve objective truth. Still, the authors argue that what historians do best is to connect with the past in order to understand present-day problems as well as the potential of the future. They maintain that we can arrive at a clearer picture of history today than was possible using methods of the past. The book traces how historians have understood their task in the past and how this conceptualization has changed through the centuries, beginning with three forms of intellectual absolutism and its consequences for historians. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Beginning in the eighteenth century, science became the basis for all truth. Therefore, science became the driving force behind the methodology of doing history, eventually replacing religion as the framework for comprehending social experience. This compelled historians to become like scientists – neutral investigators attempting to piece together events of the past exactly as they happened. This method was termed the “heroic model of science” because it made scientific geniuses into cultural heroes. Later, the idea of progress prompted historians to study the laws of human development. The last intellectual absolutism that arose in the nineteenth century came from the concept of a “nation” and the strong national sentiments that men and women drew from for a sense of identity. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The authors hearken back to the heroic model of science, asserting that it has helped shatter some of these old ways of thinking. Using methods they call scientific, historians of the twentieth century have succeeded in creating competing, multi-cultural visions of the American past. The authors argue that “a comprehensive national history is not now an educational option for the country; it is a cultural imperative” (p.295). It is vital to teach the whole of history; it is inadequate merely to select fragments. “The tension between patriotic presentation s of one’s country and accurate reconstructions of national failures remains to be probed in the future…” (242).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It is important for teachers to understand how past methodologies of history have impacted history education. A simple yet overriding lesson is that truth can never be absolute and that our view of history is colored by where we find ourselves today. Students should understand the complexity of doing history and that it is not simply one long story to be memorized. It also serves as a reminder that the search for truth is an ongoing, collective endeavor.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4736733543681822499-1932916541635413594?l=paula2010socccer.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Telling the Truth about History and Anti-Intellectualism</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth-about-history-and-anti-intellectualism.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-27T13:50:43Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-27T13:50:43Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/telling-the-truth-about-history-and-anti-intellectualism.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Telling the Truth about History&lt;/em&gt; was an interesting read. I found the discussion on relativism particularly interesting. The authors’ accurately portrayed how relativism can lead to form of nihilism with regard to history. The fear that history is polluted by relativism leads to a rejection of all histories, no matter how sound. It has become very prevalent lately for groups to deny the facts behind sound historical research because they do not agree with it or it makes them uncomfortable.  This form of anti-intellectualism is especially prevalent among the tea-party crowd who has based their movement on a historical event and a belief in the sanctity of the founding fathers. Tea-Party star Congresswoman Michele Bachmann, (R-&lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;MN&lt;/span&gt;), recently said, “But we also know that the very founders that wrote those documents worked tirelessly until slavery was no more in the United States, men like John Quincy Adams&amp;#8230; would not rest until slavery was extinguished in the country.” I do not need to explain to history majors what is wrong with this statement, but this gross re-writing of history for political gain is very dangerous, particularly when historians who point out the errors are derided for being part of the liberal elite, influenced by relativism. You see that this is the showstopper, ending all debate. I think that rejection is a form of nihilism. Those ivory tower elites, Appleby, Hunt and Jacob eloquently wrote in &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt;, “We are emphasizing the human need for self understanding through a coherent narrative of the past and the need for admittedly partial, objective explanations of how the past has worked.” And, “We are highlighting the need for the most objective possible explanations as the only way to move forward, perhaps not on a straight line of progress, but forward toward a more intellectually alive, democratic community, toward the society in which we would like to live.”&lt;a href=&#34;http://williambuie.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post-new.php#_ftn1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; When they say to move forward they are referring to getting beyond the intellectual absolutist methods of heroic science, progressivism, and nationalism.  In the next to the last chapter they lay out how they believe we should proceed, with methods and models like practical realism, working with science (in a non-heroic model), new theory of objectivity, psychological dynamics of knowing, narratives and languages, and the textuality of texts. These models and methods are well developed theories based on the mistakes of our predecessors and give us a good chance to get it as right as we go forward.  It is more important than ever to produce the best product we can in the face of a growing wave of anti-intellectualism, to prevent any crack in our armor for the extremist elements (left or right) in our society to exploit. If not, before too long we might hear that George Washington defeated the British with an army of archangels and was able to shoot lightning bolts out of his ass (forgive the Braveheart&amp;nbsp;reference.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;hr size=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://williambuie.wordpress.com/wp-admin/post-new.php#_ftnref1&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; Joyce Appleby, Lynn Hunt, and Margaret Jacob, &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Telling the Truth about History&lt;/span&gt; (New York: Norton, 1994),&amp;nbsp;229.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/28/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=28&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Object of Research</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/object-of-research.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-25T19:55:48Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-25T19:55:48Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/object-of-research.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;The object of my research and the subject of my argument are two concepts that seem to elude me, so I am going to present them in terms of my research topic and see what you think. Throw it against the wall if you will and see what sticks. In my research topic I am going to trace the careers/experiences of the original 1973 enlisted boot camp classes of fully integrated Coast Guard women. Why is this important or interesting you might ask?  The integration of women into the military was in many respects every bit as difficult as the integration of minorities. These women experienced a lot of discrimination and harassment and my own experience with Coast Guard women leads me to believe that there are some compelling stories of courage here that should be captured. I have a straw man of a thesis that, as time passed and the rules in society and the military changed that the treatment and opportunities for these women improved. So I think my the main object of research will be the first fully integrated Coast Guard enlisted women from the year group 1973, and the subject of my argument will be gender relations in the Coast Guard from 1973 to present. Please let me know what you think of my topic and if you think I got the object of my research and the subject of my argument correct. I also want to know if you think as a man, that I can do this topic justice. That is all for now, talk to you&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/23/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=23&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Object of Research or Subject of Argument?</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/object-of-research-or-subject-of-argument.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-21T09:20:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-21T09:20:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/object-of-research-or-subject-of-argument.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; After reading and discussing the articles assigned for this past week. I&amp;#8217;m thankful to be somewhat more clear on the differences between object of research and subject of argument. &amp;nbsp;The corollary between the two is simply that the objects of research generally act as the vehicle through which a historian arrives at his subject of argument. &amp;nbsp;A subject is wholly unsubstantiated without objects of research, and conversely, objects of research are merely pieces of evidence that necessitate a grander subjective interpretation. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; In the case of Kimberly Gauderman&amp;#8217;s article, it is not terribly hard to recognize the objects of research: the women obraje owners and their respective stake in the economy of Quito. &amp;nbsp;Using the experiences of these women, Gauderman makes a claim to the opposition of patriarchal dominance that has traditionally been afforded to Spanish colonial territories. &amp;nbsp;It seemed considerably more difficult to identify the objects of research in the book I read for the historical problem paper. &amp;nbsp;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-tab-span&#34; style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;Briefly, the book is about constitutionalism, the amending process, and the way in which amendments serve as a key indicator of changing American political thought. &amp;nbsp;Unlike either of the two assigned articles, the author chooses to partition his work into chronological divisions, divvying up constitutional amendments into eras of political change. &amp;nbsp;Therein which, the author narrates his claims by providing a plethora of political anecdotes (meetings, dialogues, conventions, court rulings) that intend to envelop the reader in the author&amp;#8217;s main claim. &amp;nbsp;Are the objects of research these political anecdotes or more broadly and simply, just the entire chronological era of political thought that the author analyzes as divided by chapter?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Another question that arose to me was whether or not the author&amp;#8217;s historiographical approach to the work was considered in analyzing his/her narrative. &amp;nbsp;The two articles we read for last class used a cultural approach, largely determining how race, gender, or class played into their respective issues/claims. &amp;nbsp;Instead, the aforementioned book on the amending process recognizes the &amp;#8216;Great Man&amp;#8217; historical approach, transitioning from one political agent or political event, straight to the next one. &amp;nbsp;Are these varying approaches relevant in narrative?&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; The other reading &lt;i&gt;The Craft of Research&lt;/i&gt; was a well-prepared, if somewhat formulaic, look at how to make a legitimate claim with full supporting reasons in the context of a lengthy research essay. &amp;nbsp;I feel like some of the most important things to take from the reading were the strategies employed by the authors in answering and responding to counter-claims by hypothetical readers. &amp;nbsp;Sometimes, I feel as if the flaw in my writing is an inability to conform my thoughts to meet the needs of my readers. &amp;nbsp;The tips offered by Booth are helpful in considering where readers will find problems with your writing, and how to construct appropriate responses to these arguments. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-3516865043739188055?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">If we knew what it was we were doing, it would not be called research, would it?</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/if-we-knew-what-it-was-we-were-doing-it-would-not-be-called-research-would-it.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-18T23:24:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-18T23:24:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/if-we-knew-what-it-was-we-were-doing-it-would-not-be-called-research-would-it.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“One can suggest that the accumulation of small investments could have been an important element in the financing of the district&amp;#8217;s main commercial enterprise.”&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This week’s readings were all about finding the object and subject of a particular argument. It was also about deciphering the structure that is used in a particular paper. The object of the research is the question that the researcher is trying to answer. The subject of the argument is how the researcher answers the question. The structure is how the researcher frames the narrative to explain their argument. The evidence that they use is how they support the argument that they are trying to explain. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In this week’s readings there were two examples these structures. The first was Kimberly Gauderman’s article on women in textiles in seventeenth century Quito. Gauderman uses a very strict structure that is framed much like a funnel. This structure also helps her to bring together her argument that women’s economic lives were not actually set apart by their gender but by their ability to use economic prosperity and work. But, what gave even more support to Guaderman’s argument was at what cost these women gained their economic stability. Her evidence through court cases and notarial records. These revealed while the elite women who actually owned may not have been involved in the day to day lives of their obraje, there were maestros of lower social status that were involved. Fueled by the demand for their textiles they pushed the indigenous people in their care very hard. An important part of this that is revealed is female-to-female relations. Women were not any easier on their female employees because they were women. In many ways they were harder, accusing them when they became pregnant. Another gender relation that is revealed is that women could hold their own in court as well as men. Gauderman’s article divulges that women gained equality but at the expense of other women’s lives. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In another article written about the working class in Victorian England, it states that &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;E.P.&lt;/span&gt; Thompson stated, “everything, from their schools to their shops, their chapels to their amusements, was turned into a battle-ground of class.” &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;E.P.&lt;/span&gt; Thompson’s object was what the determining factor behind the English crowd’s riots were. He states how they are not just an outburst determined by nothing. They were hungry because of bread prices and realized their voice in the larger political spectrum. He talks about how in thinking about economy not through capitalism but through a moral economy. Relies more on the cultural and justified reasoning behind economy then a laissez-faire type economy. His ideas are much supported because there were starving populations that did not rise up such as the Irish during the potato blight. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-1912947028752825506?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">From Quito to England</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/from-quito-to-england.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-17T02:56:03Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-17T02:56:03Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/from-quito-to-england.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This week&amp;#8217;s class began with a library lesson that seemed invaluable to the production of our theses, but was also overwhelming. The sheer amount of information out there makes me sympathize with Lord Acton, but hopefully once my topic is narrowed down I won&amp;#8217;t be so apprehensive about the research. The first reading of the week targeted this task of formulating a research question, and I can&amp;#8217;t wait to have this completed. The reading on Quito was quite a bit more manageable than that of the moral economy in England, simply because of length. In the article on Quito, Gauderman&amp;#8217;s subject was the refutation of the patriarchal label used to describe gender domination in Spanish colonies. Her article starts with a broad scope and narrows down to prove her point. She lays out women&amp;#8217;s roles in the economy in this culture, then moves to the economy of Quito, and finally to textile production. Her method is very effective and her illustrative narration keeps the reader engaged. The object of research is the &lt;em&gt;obraje&lt;/em&gt; owners and through the examination of notarial and criminal records she constructs a realistic view of them. This article accurately refuted the widely accepted label of patriarchy in this culture, and thusly her research problem was solved &amp;#8230; a historian&amp;#8217;s dream. The article regarding the moral economy in England during the 18th century was a little less engaging, but still proved and interesting point. The author refuted the spasmodic character of the food riots and did so through the lens of the worker. He successfully proved these occurrences were often supported by the community and certain officials, thusly legitimizing the workers&amp;#8217; actions. Both pieces were not only professional analyses of history, but were interesting as well. I hope my thesis can achieve this&amp;nbsp;goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/17/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=17&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Historical Reasoning</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/historical-reasoning.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-15T20:15:07Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-15T20:15:07Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/historical-reasoning.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This past weeks readings ranged from a very practical manual on writing history to the always complicated journal article. My favorite piece of the week was Leslie Reagan&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;When Abortion was a Crime&lt;/em&gt;. To begin with, I found it very interesting that she presented a history from a period that had yet to be thoroughly examined. This lack of examination stemmed from the people assuming that since abortion was illegal, it didn&amp;#8217;t happen. This assumption seems silly but until Reagan researched the subject, the question of abortion seems to be unexamined during that period. I think this example of a simple inquest could open up many more fields of history, and also present interesting topics. Her illustrative and reasoning skills are also unbelievable. The amount of information she obtains from her sources is fascinating and would clearly be a great skill to possess in a historian&amp;#8217;s toolbox. It seems that she uses both inductive and deductive methods to reach her conclusions and these are used effectively throughout the book. The objectivity with which she tackles the polarizing issue of abortion also shows a mastery of historical writing. Her opinion on the issue is conspicuously absent, and the evidence for her analysis is rock&amp;nbsp;solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journal article addressed the unbelievably complex concept of structure and provided a better &amp;#8220;definition&amp;#8221; of what that was. It seems to me that the concept of structures is a web of interaction with no discernible start or end, thusly making it quite dynamic. I look forward to gaining further understanding on this&amp;nbsp;topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/14/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=14&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Is the foreign so foreign?</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/is-the-foreign-so-foreign.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-08T05:32:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-08T05:32:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/is-the-foreign-so-foreign.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;“Structures then are “virtual” and are put into practice in the production and reproduction of social life.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The Leslie Reagan book in an essence describes the idea of history being a foreign country. The vocabulary and their view on life were completely different. But, through the interpretation that Raegan gives, she is able to give understanding and significance to a time that is foreign to the modern reader. She is able to point out what is significant in that time and then come up with a thesis that is relevant in a modern perspective. She is able to take a study that is centered when abortion was a crime and then make conclusions to when it became legal. She is able to give a perspective on that change that is well thought out and shows the positive and negative changes that occurred because of the legalization. This is the responsibility of the historian to take the foreign country and interpret. To give their interpretation of the events in the most unbiased way possible. Inevitably it will come out, and that is what makes historiography interesting. It is what historians do with the research they have in presenting it in their final product. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;In Sewall’s discussion of structure one of the first points he talks about is how structure can be limiting in thinking about the past. One of the best quotes he talks about this is, “A social Science trapped in an unexamined metaphor of structure tends to reduce actors to cleverly programmed automatons.” This is a huge boundary to get over as a historian. To give people of the past real human emotions. They were in some ways very much like modern humans. They had thoughts and feelings. These emotions effect their decisions, which in turn would have affected the process of events following these decisions. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Anthony Gidden’s idea of structure was the most useful to determining the importance of structure. Especially in the form of resources. Gidden’s best quote was when he stated; “resources are anything that can serve as a source of power in social interactions.” Another quote that helped to not just explain Gidden’s own ideas about structure but Sewell’s was “Structures are not the patterned social practices that make up social systems, but the principles that pattern these practices.” The metaphor of the working class in England could work in this situation. For the point of structure it is not the actual social structure of that society it was the decisions and then the eventual revolution that put them in that situation. Gidden puts it very simply as the process that is the structure. This fits into agency because agency then is the situation that the structure has put them in. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-1613187504344447476?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Blog 3</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/blog-3.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-07T03:19:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-07T03:19:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/blog-3.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;William Sewell lays out a much more complex theory of structure than I had considered last week. &amp;nbsp;In his view, every structure that controls some aspect of social life can also be seen as structuring some other aspect. &amp;nbsp;Thus, structures can be seen as numerous and overlapping in many respects. &amp;nbsp;Sewell&amp;#8217;s conceptualization of heterogeneous structures plays heavily into his determination to prove structural change is possible. &amp;nbsp;Indeed, Sewell puts together a formulaic argument based on his proposed five axioms, which posits a sustaining schemas/resources duality that control social action. &amp;nbsp;Structural change is possible because structures are a product of the social action that they control; yet that production is neither automatic nor singularly controlled. &lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;In my last blog, I talked a little bit about how a government could be seen as a limiting structure in its tension with personal agency. &amp;nbsp;Thus, it was refreshing to see Sewell discuss it, especially in terms of how structures harbor power, though may not be extremely well entrenched in social life. &amp;nbsp;Sewell describes the political &amp;#8216;state&amp;#8217; as relatively near the surface of social life, which to me means that political structures are normally fragile despite their large power allocations. &amp;nbsp;Sewell uses the state analogy to show that the durability of a social structure is determined more by the structure&amp;#8217;s depth than its power.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Sewell&amp;#8217;s interpretation of agency as a constituent to, rather than in opposition with, structure is confusing to me considering all we talked about in class. &amp;nbsp;Sewell says that the &amp;#8220;capacity for agency is as much a given for humans as the capacity for respiration.&amp;#8221; &amp;nbsp;Perhaps the capacity is there, but structural limitations work to oppose agency to such a degree, I don&amp;#8217;t really see how one can say that structure and agency work in accordance.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Finally, Leslie Reagan&amp;#8217;s book &lt;i&gt;When Abortion Was A Crime&lt;/i&gt; was an enjoyable read, as I felt that her narrative voice spoke for her rather than any pre-conceived bias. &amp;nbsp;I honestly don&amp;#8217;t know if Leslie Reagan is pro-choice or pro-life, but most importantly, it doesn&amp;#8217;t really matter. &amp;nbsp;It was nice to read the history of a controversial present-day issue, presented in terms of anecdotal historical evidence. &lt;br /&gt;Reagan uses a mixture of deductive and inductive reasoning to reconstruct the societal happenings that occurred as a reaction to the criminalization of abortion. &amp;nbsp;The information Reagan could gleam from the context of a conversation was intriguing in and of itself. &amp;nbsp;If Reagan hadn&amp;#8217;t provided all the stories/conversations that she did, I think her history of abortion as a crime would have been limited and incomplete, simply because of the amount she interpreted from those conversations.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-5317323383804579347?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Structure vs Agency</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/structure-vs-agency.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-05T16:19:20Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-05T16:19:20Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/structure-vs-agency.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Structure vs Agency. The journal article on structure and agency was interesting and reminded me of a debate that helped me understand the concepts. As the author indicated trying to understand structure can be difficult, but when an example is applied it becomes much clearer. The debate focused around the amount of structure and agency within the lives of African American slaves in the south. A historian by the name of Eugene Genovese argued in his book &lt;em&gt;Roll, Jordan, Roll: The World the Slaves Made &lt;/em&gt;(1974), that slaves in the South possessed agency within their lives (or some amount of freedom of choice) as evidenced by slave culture and religion. He argued that even when families were broken up other males would step in to fill the role of the protector. Wilma Dunaway wrote that very little agency existed in the life of slaves because slavery in itself was the equivalent of “social death.” I thought Dunaway won the debate when she pointed that Genovese’s agency argument was based on the model of the large plantation with lots of slaves, when in reality the majority of slaves were held on small farms in small numbers. Anyway that example helped me understand the two concepts. I have a new understanding on how the two are linked. You cannot measure one without the existence of the other and we should strive to understand the structure of the subjects and events we study.&lt;br /&gt;
Leslie Reagan’s, &lt;em&gt;When Abortion was a Crime&lt;/em&gt;, was an outstanding example of how to interpret data as presented by understanding the context of the conversations. She learned more by what was not said, than said. For example she understood that for the actual procedure to be referred to in code or to be left unspoken, was an indicator of prevalence. My only issue with that as I so ineloquently stated in class was that the people being interviewed in the inquest already understood the subject matter which might explain why they didn’t completely articulate the subject matter. That in itself caused zero problems for me because of how airtight the remainder of her research was. I hope I can put together a piece of slam dunk history like that one day. Talk to you in a couple of weeks.&amp;nbsp;–Paul.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/18/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=18&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Historiography 2</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/historiography-2.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-02T07:19:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-02T07:19:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/historiography-2.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;!--StartFragment--&gt;  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;b style=&#34;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;Historiography 2-Blog 2&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Mark Bevir stated, “We can say that the working out of objectivity is itself a profoundly historical process.”&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;This is very true given the readings and what has been stated in class. From the in class time from last week there seemed to come about two ways of looking at history. One through Historical Materialism the other through Historical Culture. From looking at this it would seem that the most egocentric way of looking at history is through Historical Materialism. Through culturism the historian interprets the culture within its own world. It does not try to compare and contrast itself to another culture. In materialism, there is always going to be a comparison against the most technologically advanced country. But, what is that technology is negative. This is what makes both sides objective. Because a historian cannot put himself or herself into the past it is physically impossible. Also the historian cannot investigate a country, which had a lower living standard than the richest country in the world at the time. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;One of the ways that I appreciated Bevir’s comments was through his idea that, “Of course, as interpretations reveal the particular character of a fact, they often partially define the way we regard the fact.” This is very true in that what the historian states in his work will shape the reader’s perception of that event until he or she reads another work about that subject and it may change. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;I am reminded through this of how this could work in a primary source work where the historian is the self telling the story. After the Battle of Gettysburg, there were many interpretations of who shot the first shot there. But, the one that was written was from the Confederate side that said the Seventh Tennessee Regiment of Archer’s Brigade shot down one of Beaufort’s cavalry. Because this was the only thing written about that particular part of the battle it was accepted. But, many years later many more accounts were written and it was officially decided that is was actually one of Beaufort’s cavalry. Because of the Tennesseans bias toward making their contribution to the battle bigger they changed their interpretation and thereby changing history. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Through the contributions of historiography, it has now become a wide field that can be argued over and interpreted time and time again. &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-6832822848362589315?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">History 307 is a Foreign Country</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/history-307-is-a-foreign-country.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-01T05:27:03Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-01T05:27:03Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/history-307-is-a-foreign-country.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;This past week&amp;#8217;s discussion began with something rather comfortable to me, footnotes. After feeling rather intellectually inadequate due to the pre-class readings, this was a welcome topic. We settled on the notion that footnotes establish the author&amp;#8217;s credibility as well as competence. We moved on to the affect the publishing industry has upon academic research and work. The ever present drive within (publication) companies for money seems to have changed the atmosphere of academic work in a negative aspect. The researcher not only desires to be published but usually needs to be in order to continue their profession. This need empowers the publisher and allows them to influence the content of the final product (i.e. footnotes, subject matter). Dr. Black then explained the levels of employment within the University in regards to professors and I honestly had no idea of the struggle for PhD&amp;#8217;s to not only gain tenure, but a reasonable living! It explained a lot about the professors I have had in the past three years and I think I could guess which ones had more stable positions. This all related to the relationship between structure and agency in historiography. This publishing/university structure was deemed to inhibit the historian&amp;#8217;s agency, and in order to have more of a free reign upon deciphering history, this must&amp;nbsp;change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This discussion then morphed into one that incorporated the readings, a time I was not looking forward to. While feeling like a lost puppy, we stumbled upon the topic of historical materialism vs. idealism. We defined materialism to mean the search for tangible explanations, in regards to historical causes, while idealism deals with the abstract. An example of materialism would be the Marxist approach to history and one of the readings addressed a specific group of scholars in Britain that followed this stringently. I feel I am oversimplifying or under-qualified, but I think I would take both approaches into consideration while writing history (Is this possible?). Our conversation then dealt with the derivation of meaning within history, and the cultural lens that must be present to do this. It seems that history is all about &lt;strong&gt;context&lt;/strong&gt;, and Dr. Black then posed the question: Can a man accurately write the history of a woman? While the sexes may differ and this has caused inaccurate historical accounts in the past, an objective approach could definitely allow a history to be written. As long as the male not only considers the culture and structures present, but also the woman&amp;#8217;s place in it, then it could be&amp;nbsp;done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel I have rambled/summarized enough and welcome enlightenment provided by my classmates and&amp;nbsp;teacher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com/6/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=gunnarforsberg.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19227696&amp;amp;post=6&amp;amp;subd=gunnarforsberg&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Blog 2</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/blog-2.html"/>
            <updated>2011-02-01T02:11:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-02-01T02:11:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/blog-2.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;For this past week&amp;#8217;s literature I decided to take notes as I was reading through it, primarily in order to help myself recognize some of the larger and interconnected ideas. &amp;nbsp;During discussion we didn&amp;#8217;t really have time to delve into Mark Bevir&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8216;web of interpretation&amp;#8217; ideas, though I found them be pretty interesting. &amp;nbsp;Bevir holds that historians seek to establish a web of interpretation, formulated in terms of agreed facts, to help explain past events. &amp;nbsp;The interpretation should be analogous to a web, in that it should be extensive and all encompassing. &amp;nbsp;In fact, I think Bevir used the terms &amp;#8216;fruitful&amp;#8217; and &amp;#8216;open&amp;#8217; to describe any historical interpretation. &amp;nbsp;It is also crucial to recognize the fluidity of any possible interpretation of the past. &amp;nbsp;Inevitably, all interpretations and theories are subject to outside criticisms. &amp;nbsp;Yet, if one has established the fruitful and fluid &amp;#8216;web&amp;#8217; of interpretation Bevir speaks of, it should be easy to incorporate opposing arguments into your own. &amp;nbsp;I wonder if Bevir would have said that historical knowledge (rooted in historical interpretation) only ever advances forward as the best, most successful interpretations continue to improve by incorporating or overcoming criticisms?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;Apple-tab-span&#34; style=&#34;white-space: pre;&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;As to what we discussed in class, I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking a bit about personal agency in history and its tensions with structure. &amp;nbsp;I know to exemplify &amp;#8216;structure&amp;#8217; we provided such ideas as funding models and disciplinary standards, which definitely do limit one&amp;#8217;s capacity to act. &amp;nbsp;However, when I hear &amp;#8216;structure&amp;#8217; that limits one&amp;#8217;s ability to act, I can&amp;#8217;t help but think of the monolithic American government. &amp;nbsp;In a supposed free society, our government tightly watches those who have the greatest agency. &amp;nbsp;For example, consider Nixon&amp;#8217;s paranoia with John Lennon and Lennon&amp;#8217;s simple message of peace. &amp;nbsp;The American government tapped Lennon&amp;#8217;s phone and had men follow him, primarily because they feared his capacity to act, his ability to impact society. &amp;nbsp;Marxist history or &amp;#8216;history from below&amp;#8217; would have one believe that limited agency is a product of your social position, rooted in an economic framework. &amp;nbsp;In my life, I feel as if I have enjoyed a great number of freedoms that have allowed me to act and affect things external to myself. &amp;nbsp;Yet, if the government intends to strip our freedoms away and keep us tied down by a massive institute, which only has its best interests in mind, what hope is there for our personal agency within society?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I had to watch a documentary on Lennon for my Cinema Studies/American Politics class, so sorry about the above rant. &amp;nbsp;See you guys Wednesday.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-4397289682156802977?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">week 2 - Marxists reading</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/week-2-marxists-reading.html"/>
            <updated>2011-01-30T04:44:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-01-30T04:44:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/week-2-marxists-reading.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;First, Marxists whether historians,sociologists or philosophers, all talk of the same thing, that is economic classes that exist in the society and how the poor are being oppressed by the elite. In this article Marxist historians try to advocate for social change by contributing to class consciousness and recovering of past experiences. I think as much as historians want to understand what really happenned in the past, we can never really know, we can only get to know or understand a certain portion of the bigger picture. Take for example,trying to understand a culture totally different from your own, even if one tries to socialize with people from that culture one can never really know exactly the ongoings of that society because we are socialized differently. Take myself as an example, an international student from Africa, first time in America, nomatter how hard i will try to understand the American culture i can never really understand all of it. Which takes us back to last week&amp;#8217;s discussion truth and accuracy. How much truth is there in historical documents and how much of it is just mere speculation? I believe that the deeper one goes with their research, the less truth there is to it and the more speculation there is. I really dont mean to be too skeptical but historians tend to take a side nomatter how unbiased they try to be,for example, the Marxists never really liked the elites, so obviousy they would take the side fo the &amp;#8220;opressed&amp;#8221;. My point here is, we as historians really need to be open minded and be able to critically analyze our sources because somewhere somehow they are bound to be biased. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;That&amp;#8217;s my story and i&amp;#8217;m sticking to it&amp;#8230;&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/4736733543681822499-5914237859970629310?l=paula2010socccer.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Objectivity</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/objectivity.html"/>
            <updated>2011-01-28T18:11:08Z</updated>
            <published>2011-01-28T18:11:08Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/objectivity.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Mark Bevir might be guilty of sophistry, but if not that, he is certainly guilty of first degree verbosity. To quote the great amateur historian Forrest Gump, “I am not a smart man,” but I will attempt to comment on/interpret his article. Let me start by saying that the Bevir piece had more -isms than my Philosophy class last semester (God I hated that class), back to Bevir and objectivity.  “No existing past exists in which to judge rival interpretations” that is why we lose all objectivity, relativism aside?  I think I understand what that means but am concerned about why it is a serious challenge to Bevir’s notion of objectivity. If I study a primary source historical document, interpret, and then write about it. My analysis will certainly be based on my current day experience, it is unavoidable. Does that mean I am not objective just because there are no interpretations from another time in which to compare my work? I agree with Bevir that like the scientists he mentions our theories should not be compared to prior work but to other work of our time. Comparisons to a prior time would help in determining the motives and value systems of the earlier historian; for example examining the influence of pseudo-science like Social Darwinism on an early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century historian’s interpretation of the Spanish American War.  What influences my work today and what might future historians say about it? I don’t care about future critics of my objectivity because the audience I am most concerned about lives in the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century.  I also agree with Bevir that when we compare our work with others we can find common ground or overlapping theories on which to try and determine fact. For me it is as simple as this, strive to be 100% objective and 100% accurate but know it is a little bit like an irrational number at some point you need to round it off and except your answer as the most accurate possible.  While complicated the article does make for an interesting debate, I just wish he would have written it in language that Forrest would have&amp;nbsp;understood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/16/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=16&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Blog 1</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/blog-1.html"/>
            <updated>2011-01-24T04:03:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-01-24T04:03:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/blog-1.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Hey guys, I&amp;#8217;m just here to briefly comment on last week&amp;#8217;s readings and discussion. &amp;nbsp;So part one of The Modern Historiography Reader was a collection of four historian&amp;#8217;s viewpoints on the scholarship of history. &amp;nbsp;Wow, that sounds extremely interesting&amp;#8230;&amp;#8230; &amp;nbsp;The first three authors pose the essential question of what exactly history is and what it is professional historians should or should not do. &amp;nbsp;Lord Acton&amp;#8217;s dilemma, in which he grappled with a moral obligation to point out the uniting and associated conditions of civilization, was intriguing when you consider what Cronon wrote in 2004. &amp;nbsp;In order to gain a real understanding of any past event, you have to analyze how each social/political aspect of the past relates to one another. &amp;nbsp;Like Cronon suggests, all historical knowledge is relational and the past is only a product of multicausal explanations. &amp;nbsp;My favorite article of part one was Carl Becker&amp;#8217;s construction of Mr. Everyman, whom in some ways employs history and historical research in his everyday life. &amp;nbsp;Becker seemed to make the vocation more accessible by showing how most everyone will at some point make use of critical research methods that characterize the historical field. &amp;nbsp;Last of the four articles is Bonnie Smith&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;What is a Historian?&amp;#8221; &amp;nbsp;Studying languages during youth, as the nineteenth century adolescences did, would have been the best way to prepare for a profession in history. &amp;nbsp;In today&amp;#8217;s world, having a familiarity with multiple languages would obviously be very beneficial to an aspiring historian. &amp;nbsp;Smith also speaks of the broad gender relations that have characterized the professional world of history. &amp;nbsp;I had no idea that many historians were considered &amp;#8220;so gendered in a way&amp;#8221; because of the significance of their wives to their historical authorship.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;The fifth part of The Modern Historiography Reader was intriguing enough, mainly because I related to James Robinson&amp;#8217;s outlook on &amp;#8216;The New History&amp;#8217;. &amp;nbsp;Don&amp;#8217;t we all hope that in some way our historical writing could be relevant to current times? &amp;nbsp;I feel like I need to write a history that is compelling enough, through fact alone, to make a reader potentially change his/her perspective on any given political or social issue.&lt;br /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Lastly, the Carnegie Essays on the Doctorate provided an interesting depiction of the requirements and work necessary to become part of the historian&amp;#8217;s guild. &amp;nbsp;The way in which Cronon divvies up the shared values of the &amp;#8216;historian&amp;#8217; helps one understand the intricacies of the professional doctorate. &amp;nbsp;Additionally, the information in the article helps shape my personal opinion of what would make a good senior dissertation topic. &amp;nbsp;For example, if one holds that history is inevitably written from a particular point of view and that this in turn shapes histories by correlating it with present politics, problems arise in potential topics. &amp;nbsp;In fact, it becomes a question or whether one could ever even delve into a historical topic of recent happening without entirely too much bias or subjectivity.&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/6064731372720731332-1808213275261298779?l=zfullert.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Historiography 1</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/historiography-1.html"/>
            <updated>2011-01-22T22:33:00Z</updated>
            <published>2011-01-22T22:33:00Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/historiography-1.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;b style=&#34;mso-bidi-font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;Historiography I&lt;o:p&gt;&lt;/o:p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Leopold von Ranke stated, “the purpose of history was to clarify our notion of the origin and nature of the state.” What are the roles of the writers of history, historians? What makes them qualified to do this?&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;These questions were all answered by the reading this week and through our class time. Historians are not supposed to just explain history but interpret it. What this actually means has evolved since the professions birth in the nineteenth century. One evolution that has made an extreme impact on myself is what James Harvey Robinson describes. He gives a very good descriptive analysis of the shift in the history field from what we described in class as the Great Man History to wanting to learn about the everyman and how he lived his life. He also describes the shift from the interest in the sensational to the interest in the normal. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;William Cronon, in his essay listed the qualifications that make up the profession and then presented his own thoughts on what should make up the training to be admitted to the historical guild. What makes Cronon’s thoughts interesting and challenging are not the list of qualifications but his own ideas. For myself they challenged my own ideas of training I will need. Cronon specifically talked about the Public History field, which is what I want to go into. He challenged the divergence that many public historians feel separates them from academia. He believes that public historians could have an academic training to understand the beginnings of the history in which they are presenting. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;One topic that was discussed in a majority of the essays was the role of bias in history and accepting the natural bias that occurs in the writing of history. For me the bias of history is what makes the profession interesting and fresh. It is what keeps the profession going and limitless. Topics such as the Civil War and World War &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;II&lt;/span&gt; are written about over and over again. But, what makes each work refreshing is the bias that occurs which makes it different from all works that came before it. Historians then analyze these works and write their own that will be analyzed in the future. &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;The key part of this is originality for the historians to keep asking new questions and interpreting in new ways. As William Cronon states, “Interpretation is as important as explanation.” Historians can all explain the events that they study. But, what sets them apart is how they analyze them and present it to the reader. Out of this interpretation questions are asked such as: “What is the larger picture?” or “Why is this important?” We also learn about the historian’s own time from their writings. For example we were able to learn about the nineteenth century and the moral codes of the time through Lord Acton’s writings.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;As Carl Becker states, “History is the memory of things said and done.”&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;Till next week, &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;matteavs&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;MsoNormal&#34;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;blogger-post-footer&#34;&gt;&lt;img width=&#39;1&#39; height=&#39;1&#39; src=&#39;https://blogger.googleusercontent.com/tracker/2167849845721184365-3906928167335977685?l=matteavs.blogspot.com&#39; alt=&#39;&#39; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
            <entry>
            <title type="html">Historiography I</title>
            <author><name>Chad Black</name></author>
            <link href="/307S2011/blog/historiography-i.html"/>
            <updated>2011-01-19T02:35:26Z</updated>
            <published>2011-01-19T02:35:26Z</published>
            <id>/307S2011/blog/historiography-i.html</id>
            
            <content type="html">
                                &lt;p&gt;Historiography- The study of how historians do history; that sounds about as exciting as watching paint dry, but  I must admit that as an historian apprentice,  I found parts of this week&amp;#8217;s readings intriguing. I particularly liked the William Cronon essay and his discussion on objectivity. While absolute objectivity should be our goal, I think it is important to realize that it is unattainable. We will never be able to study our subject matter and leave our personal beliefs and culture behind. As Cronan points out realizing historians are biased helps us to critically analyze their work, and then seek the &amp;#8220;other&amp;#8221; point of view creating a broader view and hopefully a deeper understanding of the issue.&lt;br /&gt;
Understanding our bias should not prevent us from being as objective as possible. For example, I am a Coast Guard retiree and very proud of my service and the Coast Guard&amp;#8217;s history and most of its missions. My senior thesis will probably deal with Coast Guard history. So if through the course of my research I discover something relevant to my subject matter but also unfavorable towards the Coast Guard would I publish the unfavorable information? Absolutely, for two reasons: One, because it is the right thing to do and secondly, because I would control the initial message. Another example from the other direction; I personally feel that the Coast Guard drug interdiction mission is a total failure and an enormous waste of tax payer dollars.  Were I to write on the history of this mission I would include the proponents argument as a way to strengthen my own thesis. If I found that the evidence did not support my thesis and the mission is a successful one, then I would change my position and write it that way. Again because it is the right thing to do and also when I write something I want it to be as strong as possible, not necessarily bulletproof but praiseworthy. When I say the “right thing to do” it means the right thing as a reputable historian, not in the Lord Acton moral sense of right.  I believe he crosses a line with his bias by instilling a pre-supposed moral code onto his subject matter. This could result in making the research less valid and more fantastical. For example, were Lord Acton to have discovered a primary source document which put his moral code and belief system in jeopardy would he have given it the proper credence?  I think not.&lt;br /&gt;
Cronon’s comment concerning journalists writing history was interesting because the best history book I read this year was “Unbroken” written by journalist Laura Hillenbrand. Her research was outstanding and the narrative of Louis Zamperini a  &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;WWII&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;caps&#34;&gt;POW&lt;/span&gt; was very compelling, proving that you don&amp;#8217;t have to be a historian to do great&amp;nbsp;history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all for this&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gocomments/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/comments/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godelicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/delicious/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gofacebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/facebook/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gotwitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/twitter/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/gostumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/stumble/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/godigg/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/digg/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a rel=&#34;nofollow&#34; href=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/goreddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://feeds.wordpress.com/1.0/reddit/williambuie.wordpress.com/3/&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://stats.wordpress.com/b.gif?host=williambuie.wordpress.com&amp;amp;blog=19178319&amp;amp;post=3&amp;amp;subd=williambuie&amp;amp;ref=&amp;amp;feed=1&#34; width=&#34;1&#34; height=&#34;1&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;            </content>
        </entry>
    </feed>